Benjamin Paulsen

Game Developer & Designer

Portfolio Email Phone <u>bjpaulsen.github.io</u> bjpaulse@ucsc.edu (831) 428-3680

SKILLS

Open. Respectful of different ways of thinking, open to feedback, and communicative.

Skilled. Developed in C#, C++, C, Java, Javascript, Typescript, Python, HTML, and MIPS.

Versatile. Experienced with Unity, Godot, Angular, Aseprite, PureData, UNIX, Git.

EXPERIENCE

Tech4Good Lab - Lead Developer, Undergraduate Research Fellow

JANUARY 2020 - MARCH 2021

- Lead 2 teams of 3 developers to expand Causeway, our online learning platform.
- Coordinated 3 dev teams and a design team to build Relate, a site for team-building games.
- Conducted 3 rounds of user research to get feedback and improve our features.

UC Santa Cruz, Learning Support Services - Computer Science Tutor

SEPTEMBER 2019 - MARCH 2020

- Taught groups of university students how to program, debug, and problem-solve.
- Learned how to better accommodate students with diverse needs and learning differences.

Santa Cruz Parks And Recreation, Scotts Valley Library - MAKE Lab Intern

JUNE 2018 - AUGUST 2018

- Ran popular technology showcase events at the Scotts Valley Library.
- Taught children, teens, adults, and seniors about using computers, tools and tech.

PROJECTS

Game Development Projects - Designer, Programmer, Artist

DECEMBER 2017 - PRESENT

- Developed an Escher-Like World Generator with constraint satisfaction, playable in Unity.
- Created Flock Together, a personal game about finding a family of watercolor birds, in Godot.
- Developed PewPew, a fast-paced arcade game, using Javascript and Processing.

Winner at HackACM 2019 - Hackathon Beginner Category

EDUCATION

University of California, Santa Cruz - Undergraduate in Computer Science: Game Design

Benjamin Paulsen

Game Developer & Designer

Portfolio Email Phone <u>bjpaulsen.github.io</u> bjpaulse@ucsc.edu (831) 428-3680

REFERENCES

David Lee - Faculty Advisor, Tech4Good Lab

Professor of Computational Media dlee105@ucsc.edu

Veronica Rivera - Lead Causeway Researcher, Tech4Good Lab

Phd Student, Computational Media veariver@ucsc.edu

Jaqueline Morales - Supervisor, UCSC Learning Support Services

Assistant Director of Tutoring jmoral11@ucsc.edu (310)-617-0863